<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Container version="2">
  <Name>skiptro</Name>
  <Repository>mikesilvo/skiptro:latest</Repository>
  <Registry>https://hub.docker.com/r/mikesilvo/skiptro/</Registry>
  <Network>bridge</Network>
  <Privileged>false</Privileged>
  <Shell>bash</Shell>
  <Support>https://forum.kodi.tv/showthread.php?tid=381498</Support>
  <Project>https://github.com/MikeSiLVO/skiptro</Project>
  <Overview>Automatic TV show intro and credits detection using audio fingerprinting. Scans your media library and generates skip markers that Kodi (via service.skiptro) can use to auto-skip intros during playback. Manage it from the built-in web UI.</Overview>
  <Category>MediaApp:Video Tools:</Category>
  <TemplateURL>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MikeSiLVO/skiptro-releases/main/unraid/skiptro.xml</TemplateURL>
  <Icon>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MikeSiLVO/skiptro-releases/main/unraid/skiptro-icon.png</Icon>
  <WebUI>http://[IP]:[PORT:8585]/</WebUI>
  <Beta>false</Beta>
  <DonateText>Buy me a coffee</DonateText>
  <DonateLink>https://ko-fi.com/mikesilvo</DonateLink>
  <!-- Changes section auto-generated from CHANGELOG.md during release -->
  <Changes>
[center][b]Skiptro Change Log[/b][/center]

[b]v1.1.0[/b]
A reworked Shows toolbar, Custom dialog, and Stats page, smarter TMDB matching that clears most ambiguous shows on its own and now logs each run to Activity, plus mobile scrolling and safety fixes.

[u]Web UI[/u]
- **Toolbar redesign**: filter, a Grid/List toggle, sort-by (Title, Date added, Recently scanned), the library picker, and the Scan / Custom / Validate / Match actions sit in one consistent order. Phones fold it into two compact rows and the action buttons size to their labels.
- **Custom scan/export redesign**: a Scan/Export mode toggle shows only the options that apply, and the show picker is a collapsible per-library tree with a tri-state checkbox (none, partial, all), a selected/total count, a filter, and All/Clear. The toggle and action button stay pinned while the tree scrolls. Larger touch targets on phones.
- **Confirm whole-library actions**: Scan all, Validate exports, and Verify libraries ask first, since each crawls every library and wakes idle drives. A scoped single-library scan or export still runs immediately.
- **Rename libraries**: rename a library inline on the Libraries page, or with `library rename <id> <name>` on the CLI. Display-only. The folder and detections are untouched.
- **Unified jobs bar**: one bottom bar lists all running work (scans, queued exports, and matching together), each with a Cancel. It replaces the top-right Jobs button; Activity stays the full history.
- **Stats page**: the summary tightens to a clean 2x2 of cards on phones (Intros found, Libraries, Avg confidence, Exported), and the filter gets its own row with a live "shows with scan data" count. A duplicate card was dropped.
- **Support link**: a muted Ko-fi "Support" link with a small heart in the top bar, hideable from Settings.

[u]Matching[/u]
- **Fewer manual picks**: most shows that used to need one now match on their own. Matching checks name and year, then season and episode counts, then episode-title overlap, leaving only the genuinely unclear ones for you.
- **Re-match unresolved**: re-runs matching over just the ambiguous and unmatched shows; whatever stays ambiguous opens in an auto-advancing review picker.
- **Match runs in Activity**: a completed Match all or Re-match is recorded in the Activity history with its result counts (matched, ambiguous, unmatched).

[u]CLI and Docker[/u]
- **`cleanup` command**: removes detection records for episodes whose files are gone, without touching anything still on disk.
- **Docker**: the image declares `EXPOSE 8585` so Unraid and Portainer pre-fill the web UI port.

[u]Server[/u]
- **Watcher cleans up removed episodes**: the library watcher now clears detection data for episodes deleted from local disks, on top of picking up new ones. Network shares and Unraid user shares do not report changes to apps, so those rely on scheduled scanning.

[u]Fixes[/u]
- **Blank posters**: the top rows of posters could stay blank when the list restored your scroll position, until you clicked into a show and back. They load right away now.
- **More room on phones**: the page itself scrolls now instead of an inner panel, so a mobile browser hides its toolbar as you scroll down. More screen for content, most noticeable in landscape.
- **Mobile double-tap zoom**: a stray double tap on a control (a library header, a card) no longer zooms the page; pinch-zoom still works.
- **Scroll behind dialogs**: opening a dialog no longer lets a scroll or swipe move the page underneath it, and your place is kept when you close.
- **Security**: updated the bundled SQLite native library past a high-severity advisory (GHSA-2m69-gcr7-jv3q).

[b]v1.0.0[/b]
First stable release built around the web UI. The interface moved from the desktop window to your browser, so the same Skiptro runs on Windows, a NAS, or a Docker host and you reach it from any device on your network. Databases from 0.20.x migrate automatically, with a backup written first.

[u]Web UI[/u]
- **`skiptro serve`**: full interface at http://localhost:8585 - show grid with posters, library management with a folder browser, scan and export jobs with a live queue, stats, activity log, and settings.
- **TMDB matching**: shows get proper titles and posters, with a manual picker for ambiguous matches. Fully optional - a Metadata toggle keeps Skiptro folder-based with a simple list view.
- **Duplicate handling**: the same show in multiple libraries (1080p and 4K copies) merges into one entry with per-version seasons; detection and exports stay per-file.
- **Remote access**: reach Skiptro from another device on your network. No login by default; set an API key (Settings or the `SKIPTRO_API_KEY` env var) to require one, and use a VPN or an authenticated reverse proxy for access from outside your LAN. A QR code in Settings fills the key in on a phone.
- **Built for phones**: small-screen layout throughout - wide tables become one card per row, the job queue opens as a bottom sheet, and taps no longer zoom text fields.
- **Quality of life**: A-Z jump rail, library and match-state filters that survive navigation, per-card scan indicator, queue flyout with external-scan detection, custom scan/export selection, scroll restore, and themed scrollbars.

[u]Server[/u]
- **In-app scheduler** replaces OS task schedulers and Docker cron.
- **File watcher**: scans a library automatically after new episodes appear, debounced, with no disk activity while idle.
- **Server controls**: restart and shut down from Settings.

[u]Desktop and Docker[/u]
- **Desktop is now a tray launcher**: the classic desktop pages are gone; the desktop app runs the server in the tray, opens the web UI, and can start with Windows.
- **Docker serves the web UI by default**: the old `SCAN_SCHEDULE` and `SCAN_ARGS` variables are replaced by Settings and the in-app scheduler.

[u]Fixes[/u]
- **Scan resilience**: one unscannable show (an odd filename, a corrupt file, a probe failure) no longer aborts the whole library scan. It is logged and skipped and the scan continues. This affected the CLI and Docker as well. Reported by bobrap.
- **Stale detections cleared on scan**: renaming, moving, or removing an episode could leave a stale detection behind, inflating the detected count and lingering in exports. A scan now reconciles against the current files, so it self-heals.

[b]v0.20.3[/b]

[u]CLI[/u]
- **`streams` lists mismatched episodes**: when a season has audio tracks on only some episodes, `streams` now lists which episode numbers carry the extra track and warns that a per-season stream override may break detection on the rest. Uniform seasons are unchanged (the count already says all episodes match). Requested by Hitcher.
  </Changes>

  <Config Name="WebUI" Target="8585" Default="8585" Mode="tcp"
    Description="Port for the Skiptro web UI." Type="Port" Display="always" Required="true" Mask="false">8585</Config>

  <Config Name="Appdata" Target="/root/.config/Skiptro" Default="/mnt/user/appdata/skiptro" Mode="rw"
    Description="Persistent data: scan results, library config, and database." Type="Path" Display="always" Required="true" Mask="false"/>

  <Config Name="Media" Target="/media/tv" Default="/mnt/user/TV Shows" Mode="rw"
    Description="Path to your TV show library. Must be read-write so skiptro can write .skiptro.json files alongside episodes. Add more paths below if your media is spread across multiple shares." Type="Path" Display="always" Required="true" Mask="false"/>

  <Config Name="Media Paths" Target="MEDIA_PATHS" Default="/media/tv"
    Description="Container paths to register as media libraries (comma-separated). Must match your volume mount targets above. If you add more path mappings, add the container paths here too." Type="Variable" Display="always" Required="true" Mask="false"/>

  <Config Name="API Key" Target="SKIPTRO_API_KEY" Default=""
    Description="Optional. Leave blank and the web UI is open to anyone on your network. Set a long random value to require it for access from other devices. For access from outside your LAN, use a VPN or an authenticated reverse proxy." Type="Variable" Display="advanced" Required="false" Mask="true"/>
</Container>
